# Joseph Fiore PharmD

### Clinical Pharmacist - Enclara Pharmacia

Springfield, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Joseph-Fiore-PharmD/96d3517415321703

A Doctor of Pharmacy with over 10 years of clinical experience in patient care and professional consulting who is focused on the safe and appropriate use of medications. An expert in disease state management and pharmacotherapy, evaluating adverse drug events and drug interactions, and a skilled professional who interacts daily with both physicians and nurses to provide the most accurate and up to date medical information and clinical support

### Key Strengths

Clinical Consulting • Developing and Maintaining Client Relationships • Symptom Management • Adverse Drug Evaluation and Reporting • Drug Interaction Review • Palliative Care • Power Point & Public Speaking • Six Sigma • New Hire Training • Customer Service • Formularies • Aggregate Data Review • Medical Literature Review • ICD9&10 coding • Microsoft Excel & Word Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Clinical Pharmacist**

Enclara Pharmacia - Philadelphia, PA - November 2005 to Present

- Develop relationships with key clients, specifically nurses, physicians, and medical directors and provide clinical support to create cost-effective medication care plans focusing on patient specific symptoms
- Respond to unsolicited medical information requests from healthcare professionals both verbally and in writing
- Specialize in all aspects of hospice care and provide clinical consultations and education to nurses, nurse practitioners, and physicians on medications and dosing, disease states, adverse drug events, and treatment approaches
- Pharmacotherapy Specialist of an interdisciplinary team consisting of oncologists, hospice medical directors, and nurses focusing on palliative care of hospice patients.
- Certified Enclara Pharmacia Methadone Specialist providing expert consultation on the use of methadone as a palliative analgesic
- Perform drug utilization reviews and set up prescription orders while focusing on medication misadventures
- Develop and present power point presentations, training materials, and clinical case studies to newly hired pharmacists
- Act as a Pharmacy Benefits Manager for select clients and assist them in working within their defined formularies
- Train new hires on daily functions of the Support Center, specifically handling clinical consultations

### Floating Staff Pharmacist

Sav-On Acme Pharmacy - May 2004 to 2005

- Executed all the duties of a community pharmacist with emphasis on prescription correctness, clinical appropriateness, and customer service
- · Performed comprehensive drug utilization reviews and frequently intervened on patients' behalf
- Responsible for covering the Philadelphia, Montgomery, Delaware, and Chester County district as a floating pharmacist

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Doctor of Pharmacy**

University of the Sciences in Philadelphia, The Philadelphia College of Pharmacy - Philadelphia, PA 1999 to 2004

## **Pre-Pharmacy**

West Virginia University - Morgantown, WV 1997 to 1999

**AWARDS** 

# Clinical Excellence Award September 2009 Enclara Pharmacia

# **Dean's List University of the Sciences in Philadelphia** 2003

# **Dean's List University of the Sciences in Philadelphia** 2004

CERTIFICATIONS

## Registered Pharmacist in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Presentations/Special Projects

Quality Improvement Initiative

- Member of a Six Sigma team tasked with improving call quality and efficiency of pharmacists
- Designed and implemented a pilot program improving pharmacist call quality scores and efficiency and reduced the number of adverse customer service reported events. March 2013-December 2013

Pharmacotherapy of Pain Management.

• Deliver a Power Point presentation to newly hired employees focusing on pain management in the hospice setting. July 29, 2013- present

Role of Compounded Medications in the Hospice Setting.

• Presented a lecture on the use of compounded medications specific for the hospice population. University of the Science in Philadelphia Fall 2011

Hospice of Charlotte Region Medicare Audit.

• Reviewed hundreds of patient profiles investigating billing discrepancies between Medicare and our clients. November 10, 2008- December 4, 2008

Pharmacotherapy of Dyspnea and Oral Conditions.

• Lead clinical case studies to newly hired pharmacists, which encompass all aspects of dyspnea and oral condition in the hospice population. March 2007- present

ProAmatine (Midodrine) Use in Patients with Intradialytic Hypotension.

• Power Point presentation -General Medicine Clinical Rotation Hahnemann University Hospital. April 2004

Pathophysiology and Treatment of Deep Vein Thrombosis.

Power Point presentation- General Medicine Clinical Rotation Presentation Hahnemann University Hospital.
April 2004

Drug Safety Analysis of Spontaneous and Clinical Reported Events of Hyperglycemia in Patients Taking Crestor (Rosuvastatin).

Presented findings to the Drug Safety Team at AstraZeneca. February 2004

The Off-Label use of Procrit in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus, Thalassemia, and Waldenstrom's Macroglobulinemia.

Power Point presentation to the formulary review board Keystone Mercy HealthCare. November 2003

Seizures Status Post Cerebrovascular Accidents Incidence and Recommended Treatments.

 Power Point Presentation- Intensive Care Clinical Rotation Presentation Albert Einstein Hospital. October 2003

Survey of Compliance on the Use of the Alaris Smart Pumps/Drug Safety Audit.

Presented findings to Safety Review Board Albert Einstein Hospital September 2003

Oral Risedronate in the Treatment of Paget's Disease of the Bone.

Power Point presentation- Professional Seminar, University of the Sciences in Philadelphia. April 2003